<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Home</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:54:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jchai01.github.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Davinci Resolve Linux Resources</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-comprehensive-guide-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:54:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-comprehensive-guide-linux/</guid><description>Table of Contents Link to heading Installation Debugging Alternate Installation Method H264/H265/AAC Codec Workaround FFMPEG Conversion Smart Folders with Incron Transcode Footage While Editing With Macro Magic Byte Codes Can&amp;rsquo;t Move or Maximize Resolve Window Nvidia GPU Installation Arch Specific Other Resources Installation Link to heading Go to resolve&amp;rsquo;s official site to download and run their installer. If double clicking on icon does not run the app, run the app in the terminal with /opt/resolve/bin/resolve and debug from there.</description></item><item><title>Connect to Ethernet with Manual IP in Arch Installation medium</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/arch-installation-manual-ethernet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:59:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/arch-installation-manual-ethernet/</guid><description>Arch installation medium uses systemd-networkd Edit the config file: vim /etc/systemd/network/20-ethernet.network Edit the [Network] portion in the file, write Address in CIDR notation. Remove or comment out DHCP related lines. Run systemctl restart systemd-networkd. Example:
[Network] Address=143.239.81.132/24 Gateway=143.239.81.254 DNS=143.239.1.2 If the .network config file does not exist (for e.g. outside of the installation medium), create it at /etc/systemd/network/20-ethernet.network
Minimally, the whole config file should look something like this:
[Match] Name=e* [Network] Address=143.</description></item><item><title>XFCE changes (Arch)</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/arch-xfce-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:43:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/arch-xfce-changes/</guid><description>Packages: Link to heading sudo pacman -S --needed base-devel git network-manager-applet thunar-archive-plugin wget bluez bluez-utils arc-icon-theme arc-gtk-theme unzip fuse flameshot redshift copyq tmux neovim libreoffice mpv xcape net-tools
network-manager-applet - in order to see the network icon in XFCE. thunar-archive-plugin - right click extract feature. Keyboard shortcuts Link to heading super+w: firefox super+return: terminal super+i: xfce4-settings-manager print: flameshot gui shift+print: flameshot full --clipboard --path /home/user/Pictures/screenshots super+b: pkill -USR1 '^redshift$'. Setup reference Alt+F3: xfce4-popup-whiskermenu.</description></item><item><title>Running Old Linux Executables Debugging Notes</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/running-old-linux-executable/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:14:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/running-old-linux-executable/</guid><description>Unclear Error Link to heading -l is like an alias for lib, for example: /usr/bin/ld: cannot find -lXmu: No such file or directory. Actual missing file : libXmu.so Solution: sudo apt-get install libxmu-dev reference: https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/506866/what-should-i-install-to-correct-ld-cannot-find-lgbm-and-linput-so-that-i-c Compiling Libraries Link to heading If library is not available in your package manager, need to source from internet, download and compile. After running make, the executable .so file usually goes into the lib folder from the path where it is compiled.</description></item><item><title>Redshift Guide</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/redshift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 21:57:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/redshift/</guid><description>Toggle + Location Agnostic Setup Link to heading Create/edit the file ~/.config/redshift/redshift.conf, set temp-day and temp-night to the same value. lat and lon can be set randomly as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Example:
[redshift] temp-day=3500 temp-night=3500 fade=0 location-provider=manual [manual] lat=48.864716 lon=2.349014 Set startup to run redshift. Enable toggle with pkill -USR1 '^redshift$', bind it to a hotkey.
Manual Usage Link to heading With Redshift, you can set brightness level lower than the minumum.</description></item><item><title>Toggle night light in Ubuntu</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/toggle-night-light-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 22:58:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/toggle-night-light-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>Set night light to always on Link to heading Install dconf-editor: sudo apt install dconf-editor Open dconf-editor and navigate to the key/org/gnome/settings-daemon/plugins/color/ Set night-light-schedule-automatic to false Set night-light-schedule-from to 0, and night-light-schedule-to to 24 (or any value higher than this) ref: link
Add custom shortcut to toggle night light Link to heading Use the following script:
bash -c &amp;#34;if [[ $(gsettings get org.gnome.settings-daemon.plugins.color night-light-enabled) == &amp;#34;true&amp;#34; ]]; then gsettings set org.</description></item><item><title>Setup Latest NeoVim Guide</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/neovim-setup-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 22:57:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/neovim-setup-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>Executable Link to heading Download the NeoVim tar file. Extract and copy folder into /opt/ sudo mv nvim-folder /opt Create symbolic link/symlink to /usr/local/bin sudo ln -s /opt/nvim-some-version/nvim /usr/local/bin AppImages Link to heading Download NeoVim AppImage from GitHub release page.
Rename nvim.appimage to nvim
mv nvim.appimage nvim Set the permission: chmod +x nvim Install fuse2 library if it is required to run the appimage sudo apt install libfuse2 Copy from download folder to /usr/local/bin path /usr/bin is used for apps managed by the distribution&amp;rsquo;s package manager, so it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended to copy there.</description></item><item><title>Change Timezone in Linux</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/change-timezone-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 23:58:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/change-timezone-in-linux/</guid><description>View current timezone:
timedatectl List timezones:
timedatectl list-timezones Change timezone example:
sudo timedatectl set-timezone Europe/Dublin</description></item></channel></rss>