<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Davinci Resolve on Home</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/tags/davinci-resolve/</link><description>Recent content in Davinci Resolve on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:54:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jchai01.github.io/tags/davinci-resolve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Davinci Resolve Linux Resources</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-comprehensive-guide-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 01:54:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-comprehensive-guide-linux/</guid><description>Table of Contents Link to heading Installation Debugging Alternate Installation Method H264/H265/AAC Codec Workaround FFMPEG Conversion Smart Folders with Incron Transcode Footage While Editing With Macro Magic Byte Codes Can&amp;rsquo;t Move or Maximize Resolve Window Nvidia GPU Installation Arch Specific Other Resources Installation Link to heading Go to resolve&amp;rsquo;s official site to download and run their installer. If double clicking on icon does not run the app, run the app in the terminal with /opt/resolve/bin/resolve and debug from there.</description></item><item><title>Davinci Resolve Shortcut Mappings</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-resolve-shortcut-mappings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 22:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/davinci-resolve-shortcut-mappings/</guid><description>Access the preference menu Link to heading ctrl + alt + k to access preference menu.
Changes Link to heading Split clips: change from ctrl + \ to s Trim End and Trim Start: shift + [ and shift + ] to q and w respectively. (see notes for Davinci Resolve 18) Note Link to heading Davinci Resolve version 18: Start to playhead and end to playhead: ctrl + shift + [ and ctrl + shift + ] to q and w respectively.</description></item><item><title>Resolve HEVC (H265) In Davinci Resolve</title><link>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/resolve-hevc-in-davinci-resolve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:04:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jchai01.github.io/posts/resolve-hevc-in-davinci-resolve/</guid><description>Download the HEVC extension and install it from: https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/19FWeAVWFoZUaM-14Wbt3t9lb_bIprl8b Press Win + R on your keyboard to launch the Run dialog box.Type WSReset.exe in the dialog box and press Enter. Open Microsoft Store, click the Library icon. This will be on the left side of the Store app.Check for Microsoft Store Updates. Click the Get updates button to check for available updates.If updates are available, click Update all to download and install them.</description></item></channel></rss>